Guide to the Philip Laurance Buttrick Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Philip Laurance Buttrick papers
1925-1930
MS 1655
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers are composed of photographs taken or collected by Philip Buttrick during his travels and studies. Primary subjects are grazed land in the western United States and cork oak forests in the Mediterranean region.
Buttrick, P. L. (Philip Laurence), 1886-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale Forestry Library, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Philip Laurance Buttrick Papers are composed entirely of photographs taken or collected by Buttrick during his travels or his studies of cork oak forests. Many of the photographs present views of grazed land, particularly in the western United States. The Yale Forestry Library transferred the papers to Manuscripts and Archives in 1991. The Forestry Library retains some maps of cork forests created by Buttrick while he was employed by the Armstrong Cork Company.
Biographical / Historical
Philip Laurance Buttrick, 1886 – 1945
Philip Laurance Buttrick was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on June 25, 1886. He graduated from New Haven High School and attended the Sheffield Scientific School and the Yale School of Forestry. In 1921 he received a master's degree in forestry.
Buttrick served as secretary of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association from 1923 – 1929 and from 1929 – 1931 studied the cork oak forests in the Mediterranean region for the Armstrong Cork Company of Lancaster, Pennsylvania. Later in his career he worked in various capacities for the federal government. He was a professor of forestry at the University of Georgia from 1937 – 1939. Buttrick wrote many articles for forestry journals and was the author of Public and Semi-Public Lands of Connecticut (1930) and Forest Economics and Finance (1943). He died in Dover, Delaware on April 5, 1945.
Cork oak; Grazing; Photographs; Foresters; Buttrick, P. L. (Philip Laurence), 1886-
- Inventory
  - Photographs
    - Grazed pine seedlings, Cocono National Forest, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arizona, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Apache National Forest, Arizona, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - New Mexico, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Kaibab Plateau National Forest, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Grazing in France, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Grazing in New England (New Hampshire), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Grazing in Catskill Mountains, Woodstock, NY, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Grazed cork forest in Spain, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Germany, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)